Human Nutrition Research Center (HNRC) News UP231
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Human Nutrition Research Center (HNRC) News
1988 -- 1991
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Jean Mayer USDA Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging
UP231
0.25 Linear Feet
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains a newsletter for the staff of the USDA Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging. Includes a calendar of events, news items, and announcements.
Biographical / Historical
The Tufts USDA Human Nutrition Research Center was renamed in honor of former Tufts President, Dr. Jean Mayer, in 1994. The HNRC is operated by Tufts University under the authority of the USDA as a government-owned, contractor-operated facility. The HNRC, situated in downtown Boston on the Tufts Health Sciences campus, opened officially in November 1982.
The HNRC was founded through the advocacy of Jean Mayer, Tufts president and renowned nutritionist. The center's placement in New England was chosen because the large population of older citizens, the variety of ethnic and economic groups, and its urban/rural character make it a microcosm of the US as a whole.
The HNRC is located on the corner of Stuart and Washington Streets on the Boston campus in a building constructed to house the center in 1982. The building was designed by Shepley, Bulfinch, Richardson, and Abbott, and was dedicated in November 5, 1982. Prior to that time the center's activities were housed elsewhere on the Boston campus.
- HNRC News, 1988 -- 1991; UP231.001; 0.25 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains a newsletter for the staff of the USDA Human Nutrition Research Center on Aging. It includes a calendar of events, news items, and announcements.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - HNRC News, 1988-01; UP231.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1988-04; UP231.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1988-10; UP231.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1989-06; UP231.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1989-07; UP231.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1989-08; UP231.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1989-09; UP231.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1989-10; UP231.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1989-11; UP231.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1989-12; UP231.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1990-01; UP231.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1990-02; UP231.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1990-07; UP231.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1990-09; UP231.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - HNRC News, 1991-02; UP231.001.001.00015 (Box 1)